Nick Bable

Product Designer

Overview

For the past four years, I've had the opportunity to work with teams to design user-centered experiences at both agency and product companies. I enjoy finding elegant solutions to complex problems that strike a balance between solving user needs and meeting the goals of the business.

I currently design products at Mailchimp with a focus on helping small businesses organize and segment their audiences in order to manage their contacts and create better targeted marketing.

Experience

Mailchimp, Product Designer · May 2017 - Current

Audience Management Domain

Search & Segmentation Squad

I'm currently collaborating with a team of cross functional peers to redesign our segmentation experience, which gives customers the ability to target subsets of their audience based on their data.

I've helped the team define problems through ideation and design studios, iterated through ux and visual designs, and collaborated with research to prototype and test concepts with users in order to validate hypotheses.

Organize Squad

Responsible for designing and improving list management and tag tools as part of the CRM for customers. Launched the Audience Dashboard which provides users insights to target segments of their audience. Worked with team of engineers to design and deliver Tagged sign-ups on Landing Pages, helping users to organize incoming contacts.

My role was to design the user experience, collaborate with research to test concepts, and ultimately work alongside engineers to deliver the visual and experience designs.

Marketing Experience Domain

Mailchimp.com

Designed end-to-end customer experience from social media in the wild, to the front door of the app. Partnered with cross functional peers and several external agencies to redesign Mailchimps marketing site, and implement the rebrand into the new site's experience.

My role for the marketing site redesign was to work with engineers to help define our modular site templates and modules in the new brand style, develop our simplified UI illustrations, and implement pages using our new CMS, Contentful.

Look Listen, Product Designer • May 2016 – April 2017

Crafted digital and physical experiences for multinational clients and boutique brands. Responsible for visual design of web and mobile apps, websites, and brand campaigns.

Georgia State University, Designer · July 2016 - May 2017

Designed and developed web pages for Art and Design website. Produced digital and print assets including posters, brochures and other print materials for Ernest G. Welch Gallery shows and events.

Contact

nbable0@gmail.com nickbable.com 678.662.5455

Education

Georgia State University BFA Art & Design

UX Skills

User experience
Visual design
Wireframing
Prototyping
Information architecture
User interviews
Usability testing
Journey mapping
Discovery
Design Thinking
Facilitation

Software

Figma

Miro

Sketch

InVision

Abstract Principle

Framer

Photoshop

Illustrator

After Effects

HTML

CSS

Javascript